Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Markle.
My name is Catherine and today we're
talking a little bit about more small talk.
That's right, we're going
to continue our series.
This is part 9, so we're coming
close to the end of our 10 part series.
And today we're following
Melissa and Michelle as they
discuss very casually
their personal life
specifically about their
marriages or getting married.
That's right, so this one's a little
bit more difficult than the last few.
Let's take a listen to
the dialogue and when
we come back we'll be talking about
some of those phrases that you heard.
Hey Michelle, jump in quick,
exploring out there. Oh, hi Melissa.
Are you going to the conference too?
I was planning to pick up Mr. Campbell.
Yes, he told me. We need to pick him up
at his hotel and then go to the conference.
Oh, I see. Okay, so I heard you
got married. Congratulations.
Oh, thank you. I'm very
excited. We were going
to get married next
year, but then we decided
to get married on holiday instead.
It was wonderful. That sounds so romantic.
Jack and I were hoping
to get married in Europe
next year, but we had
to postpone our plans.
We just don't have the
money. I know what you mean.
I think Shanghai is getting
more and more expensive.
Don't you? I sure do.
In my opinion, it's actually becoming
more expensive than back home.
Definitely.
Oh, there's Mr. Campbell.
Driver, can you stop here, please?
All right, we're back.
So a lot of interesting
phrases in this dialogue
more than vocab.
So we're going to have
two fluency builders.
Let's start with
the first one now.
Fluency Builder.
The first phrase in
today's fluency builder
is the phrase jump in. So Melissa says,
hey, Michelle, jump in quick. That's right.
So Melissa is actually
in a taxi and that's why
she's saying, jump in
quick. So she is directing
Michelle to do something.
She's saying, jump in.
So it's actually her telling
Melissa, get in the car.
That's right.
And so we can use this
phrase to jump in somewhere,
which means you're
going to do it very quick
quickly yet to go somewhere
to get in a place very quickly.
We could say it about a cab.
We could also say it about a swimming
pool. Maybe I'm swimming in the water.
And I say, Marco,
jump in the water's nice.
That's right. Or maybe you
just got back from the gym
and you're going to
jump in the shower really
quick and before you go out again, you're
not actually going to jump like you jump
the action, but you're
going to get into the
shower very quickly. That's right. And of
course, Melissa tells Michelle to jump in
the cab quickly because it's pouring
out there. It's pouring, what's pouring?
The pouring, pouring
water, pouring wine.
That's right. It's actually, yeah,
it's pouring water out there.
It means it's raining
very, very hard.
Okay. So it's not just
drizzling a little little bit.
It's raining very hard. It's pouring
rain. Okay. So we don't have to say
the word rain. We can
just say it's pouring.
That's right. As you
can see in that sentence,
Melissa doesn't say
at any time it's raining,
but we understand that
when somebody says,
it's pouring out there,
you know that it means
it's raining very hard.
Can't be chocolate.
Can't be chocolate can't
be dogs or cats, right?
No. All right. So Michelle gets in the
cab and she says, well, we have to pick up
Mr. Campbell, Mr. Campbell.
And Melissa says,
yep, we need to pick
him up at the hotel.
All right. The verb
here is to pick up.
Now we want to just
remember this as a phrasal verb.
You pick someone up in your car.
You could even pick
someone up on your bicycle.
That's right. That's right.
So, but you can see that
you can say we need to pick
up Tommy at the hotel or you can
say we need to pick Tommy
up. So you can use it both ways.
You can put the noun
in between or after.
So can you pick me
up at five? Right. Right.
Or can you pick up the
clothes at the, the dry cleaners?
Right. It means to go collect
something or someone.
So you can use it
in different ways.
You can put the noun between
pickup or you can put it after.
And all right. So they're going to go
pick up Mr. Campbell. Now they're talking.
Well, they're kind of
gossiping a little bit.
They said, well, I
heard you got married.
All right. So I heard now this is a very,
very common way to start a sentence that
might have some gossip
in it. So I'm going to
say something that
might or might not be true.
That's right. So
you're not really sure
if it's true or not. So
this is why you start
with the sentence. I
heard that something,
something, something.
So in this case, she
said, I heard you got married or I heard
you got married because I'm, I'm basically
saying, well, some
rumor made it to me and I,
and I heard that you got
married, but I'm not sure.
So she's asking,
did you get married?
So congratulations.
That's right. That's right.
So it's a very common
way of starting a sentence
when you are talking to
someone and maybe you
want them to confirm
this news or this gossip
or this rumor is true or not.
I heard you got a promotion.
That's right. Congratulations.
So that's the way that
you use this phrase.
I heard you or well, if
you're using another
person, I heard that a Tom got divorced.
I heard Susie had a baby. That's right.
All right. So that's all for the first part
of Fluency Builder. Let's take a break and
we'll be back in a bit with part two.
Hey, Michelle. Jump in quick. It's pouring
out there. Oh, hi, Melissa. Are you going
to the conference too? I
was planning to pick up Mr.
Campbell. Yes, he
told me. We need
to pick him up at his hotel and then go to
the conference. Oh, I see. Okay. So I heard
you got married. Congratulations. Oh, thank
you. I'm very excited. We were going to get
married next year, but
then we decided to get
married on holiday
instead. It was wonderful.
That sounds so
romantic. Jack and I were
hoping to get married
in Europe next year, but
we had to postpone our plans.
We just don't have the money.
I know what to mean.
I think Shanghai is getting
more and more expensive.
Don't you? I sure
do. In my opinion, it's
actually becoming more expensive than back
home. Definitely. Oh, there's Mr. Campbell.
Driver, can you stop
here, please? All right.
So now we're back with
part two of Fluency Builder.
Let's get started with the
first phrase when she says
that they got married on
holiday. What does that mean?
On holiday is another
way of saying on vacation.
So while we were having a
holiday somewhere, this happened.
So you could say we decided
to get married on holiday.
That means when they were traveling, when
they were on vacation, they got married.
So it's kind of more of a British way of
saying right on holiday. Yes, you could
say, you know, where
did you go on holiday?
But maybe in America, we'd prefer to say
where did you go on vacation on vacation?
So both are correct. You
can say we got married while
on holiday or we got
married while on vacation.
Both are correct. That's just a little
bit of difference between British English
and American English.
And then moving on, she
said, well, they also
wanted to get married.
Michelle did, but they had
to postpone their wedding.
Okay. To postpone something
means to wait until later to do it.
So you maybe want to do it
today, but it's raining today.
So you have to
postpone until next week.
That's right. So it's
kind of like you had
to delay you had to
wait. Yeah, that's right.
So you could say that
because of bad weather,
the picnic will be
postponed until next month.
Okay. So that's the way that you postpone
now. It's interesting because you have a
pee in between there.
So it's postponed.
Yeah, it's an interesting
word to pronounce.
Okay. And well, they
also had to postpone it
because of money. You know, it's just very
expensive and Melissa agrees by saying, I
know what you mean.
I know what you mean.
Now, this is a really
common phrase.
And this is something you'll hear
with more relaxed conversations
between friends. It means I understand
the situation or I feel the same way.
So in this case, we just
don't have the money.
Melissa is saying, I
know what you mean.
It means I'm having a
hard time with money too.
I don't have much
money either. That's right.
So you understand
what she's talking about.
You also agree. I
know what you mean.
That's just a way of agreeing
with someone. All right.
And then she goes on
to confirm what Michelle is
saying by saying, I think Shanghai is
getting more and more expensive. All right.
Um, this is a really, really
key sentence structure here.
We have more and
more, more and more.
And then after that,
we have an adjective.
So, um, the structure is
more and more adjective.
So more and more spicy, more and more funny,
more and more expensive. Um, so in this
case, the city is more
expensive than it was before.
That's right. And it's still
getting more expensive.
That's right.
That's the main idea when
you use this structure is that
when you say more and
more and then you add
an adjective, such as expensive or beautiful,
it means that it continues to grow.
It continues to get more
expensive or more beautiful
or or more difficult.
But remember that we
are using adjectives
here that are when you're
using the comparative,
you can't say, for
example, you can use
funny. You can't say you
are getting more and more
funny because obviously
the comparative
for funny is funnier.
So it would just be careful
with that one because
it could be a
little bit confusing.
All right. So and to finish
off our fluency builder,
we have Michelle who
agrees with Melissa
and says, yeah, you
know, I think Shanghai is
getting more expensive and she says,
I sure do. So she's basically agreeing.
She's saying, yes, that's
true. Uh huh. But why, why
do she say I sure do? Why don't she say
agree? I agree or yeah, you're right. Well,
she doesn't have to say it because she says
I do. She's the question before that was,
I think something,
something, don't you?
And she says, I do.
And then think that.
So it's assumed that she also thinks this.
She's answering a question. That's right.
So it's an interesting way
of asking a question when
you say, um, I think
this city is beautiful.
Don't you? So the proper way to answer that
would be, I do or I sure do. All right.
So that's all the time we
have for fluency builder.
Let's listen to our
dialogue one last time.
Are you going to
the conference too?
I was planning to pick up
Mr. Campbell. Yes, he told
me, we need to pick him up at his hotel and
then go to the conference. Oh, I see. Okay.
So I heard you got
married. Congratulations.
Oh, thank you. I'm
very excited. We were
going to get married next year. But then we
decided to get married on holiday instead.
It was wonderful. That
sounds so romantic.
Jack and I were helping
to get married in Europe
next year, but we had
to postpone our plans.
We just don't have the money.
I know what you mean. I
think Shanghai is getting more
and more expensive.
Don't you? I sure do.
In my opinion, it's
actually becoming more
expensive than back
home. Definitely. Oh, there's
Mr. Campbell. Driver,
can you stop here, please?
All right. So we're
reaching the end of
our small talk series.
In this case, it's two
women who are talking
about their personal lives.
And not only that, they're talking about
weddings and they're talking about money.
So this is a very
interesting way to talk
about these very common
topics, personal life,
love and especially
money. But I remember in
American culture, these
are the kinds of things
you would only talk
to your friends about.
You wouldn't really
want to talk to strangers
about money, personal
life, marriage, because
those are considered
private. So be careful
when you're talking to people. You don't
know very well. That's right. That's right.
And actually, your
feedback was very
interesting when we
discussed about if it's okay
to ask, for example, a
woman, her age or her
weight or a man's salary. So in most places,
you said that it wasn't really correct.
But this is the very
interesting thing about the
cultural differences
and how people can,
you know, what is
appropriate to talk about.
That's right. So
again, if you have any
questions or comments
about the things we talked
about here today, or
any of our older lessons
about small talk,
please just let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
All right, guys. We'll see you there. Bye.